Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we're talking
about where people
come from or nationalities.
That's right many people come from many
different countries just like our listeners
and there are specific words
or adjectives and nouns to
describe people like for example
somebody who is from China.
A Chinese person. Mm-hmm. That's right.
So in your case Marco
you are an Ecuadorian.
That's right. So that means I
come from the country Ecuador.
I, on the other hand, I'm an American.
I come from America.
That's right. So we have
a lot of these examples.
Why don't we jump
into the dialogue.
Let's see where all of the
people from this international
class are from and we'll
be back to talk about it.
Hey, how's your
first day of class?
I'm a level two and I'm
loving my classes semester.
It's great being in a class
of international students.
Mine was okay. Except that no
one in my class speaks English.
I guess it will force me to
converse in Chinese more in
class so at least I should
improve a lot this semester.
That's both fortunate and unfortunate.
It's the United Nations in my class.
We have people from all over the world.
There are three Germans,
a pole, a scot, two French,
an American, a Brazilian, a
Chilean, a New Zealander.
Though he prefers to call himself
a Kiwi, who else do we have?
Oh, we have a Moroccan, a Tagalese,
a Pakistani, and two Indonesian's.
That's quite the
array of nationalities.
Everyone in my class
is from Asia. Except me.
There are a few South Koreans,
several Japanese, Malaysian,
Thai, Singaporean, Filipino,
Kazakhstani, and one Russian.
Well, I think you're
pretty lucky actually.
You'll have the opportunity to
learn so much about Asian culture.
I guess so. But I think it's
going to be hard to relate
to my classmates, especially
with the language barrier.
I think I might change classes.
Don't! Stay the course! Your spoken
Chinese will be eternally grateful.
I bet you it will even surpass
mine with all that practice.
I highly doubt it.
Your girlfriend is Chinese.
Well, there is that, yes.
So the student jokes that their
class is kind of like the United Nations.
So it does sound like it. We have
so many different nationalities
that we're going to look at
them in two groups today.
But the United Nations, as you know, is
a political group that has people from all
over the world who make decisions about
politics and the environment, things like that.
That's right. So why
don't we take a look at
these nationalities now
on language takeaway?
Language takeaway?
The first few are from Europe. So
these are some European nationalities.
We've got German.
Where's a German from?
A German is from Germany. Okay. So next to
Germany, we have another country, Poland.
What do we call a person from Poland?
You call that person a poll.
So is this for a woman and a
man or is this just one gender?
Yeah, it's for both. Okay. So, a girl
that's from Poland would be also a poll.
Now someone that comes from Scotland,
on the other hand, that would be a Scott.
Or if it's a man, a Scotsman.
Scotsman. Okay. Now this is
interesting because we are mentioning
the nouns of these nationalities
like, for example, German.
Now when we took a
look at poll from Poland,
what would be the
adjective? Do I say I am poll?
I am Polish.
Okay.
Or if you want to use
the noun, I am a poll.
But the adjective can be used for things
as well. I love to eat Polish sausages.
Okay. Or for example,
or something from
Scotland, you can say,
I love Scottish whiskey.
Or I love Scottish kilts. Those skirts.
All right. So that's the adjective.
But in the case of France,
the country of France,
we have to say, as a
noun, he is a Frenchman.
Okay. And if it's a woman, a French woman.
That's right. Or in the case of an
adjective, I love to eat French bread.
Okay. Now moving on to South America, we
took a look at a Brazilian and a Chilean.
Okay. So Brazil, Brazilian, in this
country, there are many Brazilians.
And Chile or Chile, as many Americans
say, has people called Chileans.
Some people say Chilean. So I don't know.
I guess the accent varies a little bit.
Now what do we move back
to the other side of the world?
We have a New Zealander. All right.
So many of you have heard of Australia.
Maybe New Zealand is not as famous.
It's a small country near Australia.
And the people who come from
there are called New Zealanders.
It's very hard to say
those sometimes, especially
when we have to use the
adjective, New Zealand.
That's right. So the students said
he prefers to call himself a kiwi.
All right. So kiwi
was a special kind of
bird that could only be
found in New Zealand.
And so this became a very
popular symbol for New Zealand.
And now people from New
Zealand call themselves kiwis.
So I could say I have many kiwi friends.
That's right. Okay. Kiwis.
So now if we go to the African
continent, we have Moroccan and totalis.
So Morocco is in North Africa.
And a person who comes
from there is Moroccan.
You can also say I like to eat
Moroccan food, which is very popular.
But when we talk about the country, Togo,
what do we call a person from that country?
Togo leaves. Togo leaves.
Okay. So it's Togo.
That's the way you pronounce it.
Because if you look at it, I would say to
go, right, but it's not to go. It's Togo.
Or as my French speaking
friend would say, Togo.
That's right.
All right.
So that's our first set of nationalities.
Let's listen to today's dialogue
one more time and we'll
be back in a moment to
discuss the other nationalities.
Hey, how's your first day of class?
I'm a level two and I'm
loving my classes semester.
It's great being in a class
of international students.
Mine was okay. Except that no
one in my class speaks English.
I guess it will force me to
converse in Chinese more in class,
so at least I should
improve a lot this semester.
That's both fortunate and unfortunate.
It's the United Nations in my class.
We have people from all over the world.
There are three Germans,
a pole, a scot, two French,
an American, a
Brazilian, a Chilean, a New
Zealander, though he
prefers to call himself a Kiwi.
Who else do we have?
Oh, we have a Moroccan,
a Togelies, a Pakistani,
and two Indonesian's.
That's quite the array of nationalities.
Everyone in my class
is from Asia, except me.
There are a few South Koreans,
several Japanese, Malaysian, Thai,
Singaporean, Filipino,
Kazakhstani, and one Russian.
Well, I think you're
pretty lucky, actually.
You'll have the opportunity to
learn so much about Asian culture.
I guess so, but I think it's
going to be hard to relate
to my classmates, especially
with the language barrier.
I think I might change classes.
Don't! Stay the course!
American Chinese will
be eternally grateful.
I bet you it'll even surpass
mine with all that practice.
I highly doubt it.
Your girlfriend is Chinese.
Well, there is that, yes.
All right, we're back, so now we have
more nationalities prepared for you,
so let's take a look at those now
on language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway.
We're in Asia for this
part of today's lesson,
so we're going to start with
a country called Pakistan.
What do we call the people from Pakistan?
We say they are Pakistani.
Okay, so in Chicago, for
example, there are many Pakistanis.
Okay, and moving on to
Southeast Asia, we have Indonesians.
All right, Indonesia is the country, and
people who come from there are Indonesian.
Okay, very good.
Now if we go back to the North
part of Asia, we have South Koreans.
So we have North and
South Korea on our maps.
A person from North Korea is North Korean,
and a person from South
Korea is South Korean.
It's kind of like that
same structure American,
Brazilian Korean.
Very good.
And moving to the island
of Japan, we have Japanese.
So this is an adjective we're
talking about a Japanese person.
He is Japanese, or we can also talk about
the food, like sushi, is Japanese food.
That's right.
Okay, moving back to Southeast
Asia, again, we have Malaysia.
So people from Malaysia
are called Malaysian.
Okay, again, with this pattern, Malaysian.
Korean.
That's right.
And I think you say Malaysian
food, or you say Malay.
I've heard some people say Malay.
I've said Malaysian food generally, but
Malay, I think, is one of the languages,
and I think it's an
ethnic group as well.
So you can have Malay people
in Singapore, for example.
Okay.
And actually, we have Thai
people and Singaporeans.
So we have two countries.
They're Thailand and Singapore.
So Thai is the adjective to describe
things that come from Thailand.
It's kind of unusual.
It doesn't fit that
pattern that I mentioned.
But it's a very important one to remember
if you like to eat food from this country.
Thai food.
Yeah, excellent food.
And Singaporean food is also pretty good.
And people from Singapore
are also called Singaporean.
Here, we've got a very tricky one.
We've got the country, the Philippines.
What do you call a person
from the Philippines?
So the Philippines is actually
spelled PHI, like Philippines, right?
But if somebody is from the
Philippines, we say Filipino with an F.
All right, Filipino.
This is interesting, especially for
people who are native Spanish speakers
because the Philippines was a
Spanish colony for a very long time.
And so you might hear someone
refer to himself as a Filipino.
He's a man.
Or if she is a woman, a Filipino.
So this is very similar
to the Spanish structure
of having a gender
on the end of the word.
That's right.
And while now we're moving
on to Kazakhstan and Russia.
We have people that are
from Kazakhstan and Russia.
And we say they are Kazakhstani.
So this is very common in that part of
the world to end the adjective in an eye.
Like Afghanistan, Afghanistan, Afghanistan,
Pakistani, Kazakhstan, Kazakhstani.
And so these are the
stands, the former USSR.
That's right.
So this is a very important
structure to remember.
But Russia is pretty easy.
Yeah, people from Russia, you say they
are Russian or you have Russian food.
Real Russian food.
All right, so we have a lot of
different nationalities there.
And obviously we didn't cover all of them.
I think, I don't know,
maybe 200 nationalities.
So why don't we listen
to the dialogue again?
And we'll be back to talk a little bit
more about this really interesting topic.
Hey, how's your first day of class?
I'm a level two and I'm
loving my class this semester.
It's great being in a class
of international students.
Mine was okay.
Except that no one in
my class speaks English.
I guess it will force me to
converse in Chinese more in class,
so at least I should
improve a lot this semester.
That's both fortunate and unfortunate.
It's the United Nations in my class.
We have people from all over the world.
There are three Germans,
a pole, a scot, two French,
an American, a
Brazilian, a Chilean, a New
Zealander, though he
prefers to call himself a kiwi.
Who else do we have?
Oh, we have a Moroccan,
a Tagalese, a Pakistani,
and two Indonesian's.
That's quite the array of nationalities.
Everyone in my class
is from Asia, except me.
There are a few South Koreans,
several Japanese, Malaysian,
Thai, Singaporean, Filipino,
Kazakhstani, and one Russian.
Well, I think you're
pretty lucky, actually.
You'll have the opportunity to
learn so much about Asian culture.
I guess so, but I think it's going to
be hard to relate to my classmates.
Especially with the language barrier.
I think I might change classes.
Don't. Stay the course.
Your spoken Chinese
will be eternally grateful.
I bet you it'll even surpass
mine with all that practice.
I highly doubt it.
Your girlfriend is Chinese.
Well, there is that, yes.
All right, we're back, so
talking about nationalities,
I think there's one that we didn't
mention that's very, very popular.
People from Ireland.
Okay, so people from
Ireland are called Irish.
Irish.
The Irish, or Irishman.
This is a similar
structure to a lot of those
countries in Northern Europe,
like Sweden and Finland.
That's right, so somebody from
Sweden would be called Swedish.
Yes, or a Swede is the noun, so I
love to eat Swedish food like salmon.
But the similar structure
applies to Finland in Finland.
They're very famous
for their Finnish bread.
Finnish, so that's the way that you
say Finnish, with double-n, right?
That's right, it's not like
I finished my homework.
It's like F-I-N-N-I-S-H, Finnish.
Finnish.
Now, what about people from Denmark?
They are Danish.
Danish.
And what about people from Norway?
They are Norwegian, so that's
one that does not fit the pattern.
And this is a very interesting one
that also doesn't fit the pattern at all.
People from Holland.
Okay, so Holland, as a
country, has two names.
We sometimes say Holland.
We sometimes say the Netherlands.
But a person who comes
from Holland is called Dutch.
Dutch.
That's right, so it doesn't
have to do with neither Holland.
You don't say a whole
lander or Netherlands.
You don't say Netherlands.
It's Dutch.
Dutch.
You also read this on cookie tins, you know,
boxes for cookies, Dutch style cookies.
That's right.
Alright, so that's a very important moment.
It comes to food.
But we're very curious to hear
about where you come from.
You should try some of the new vocabulary
words that we have introduced here.
Talk about your friends or your family.
But also, tell us if we didn't
include your nationality.
That's right.
Alright, so we'll see you guys there.
Englishpot.com.
Bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]